

28A Daventry St, Waterview, Auckland 1026

Mobile: 021 08899356 mrfuyuan@gmail.com

https://mrfu.me/ https://github.com/mrfufufu

CAREER OBJECTIVE

I am currently studying Graduate Diploma in Computing at Unitec. I had over four years' experience of Android development, also familiar with iOS platform; solid knowledge of Git and Subversion. I have a blogging site about technologies, which recorded some of my development experiences. I am competent in programming practice and passionate on new technologies.

SKILLS & PROFILE

- Good understanding of mobile development.
- Familiar with Java, C#, Swift, HTML5, JavaScript, Objective-C; Auto Layout on iOS.
- Solid knowledge of REST API design, Git and Subversion.
- · Work on bug fixing and improving application performance.
- Full of framework and component implementation experience.
- Experience in project structure and Android/iOS Design standard.
- Continuously discover, evaluate and implement new technologies to maximise development efficiency.
- Technology sharing[1] [2] [3], and Open Source Code.

EDUCATION

Graduate Diploma in Computing (Software Development) 2017 -

2017 - 2018 (expected)

United Institute of Technology, Auckland, New Zealand

Bachelor of Engineering (Communication Engineering)

2009 - 2013

Zhijiang College of Zhejiang University of Technology, Hangzhou, China

EXPERIENCE

Android Developer (Team leader)

July 2014 - July 2017

Hangzhou Taofenba Network Technology Co.,Ltd.

China

- Designed and built applications for the Android platform: Xingxing and Haihu apps.
- Mainly focus on Android platform, but also work on HTML5 and iOS platform.

Android Developer (Junior)

April 2013 - June 2014

Hangzhou Enjoyor Wise Information Technology of 120 group Co., Ltd.

China

 Developed E-Health(App) based on Windows platform (WinForm) and an Android Application.

PROJECTS

1. Haihu for Android

July 2015 - July 2017

It is a shopping app. Data of products was retrieved from outbound websites (amazon.com, amazon.co.jp, 6pm.com etc.). We used the Spider (Web Crawler) to get products information which are shown on our app. Users buy products through Alipay (a Chinese paypal) instead of VISA or MasterCard (Alipay is overwhelmingly used in China).

As the Android team leader, I was responsible for

- The development and maintenance of the Android development platform*.
- Designed REST API for mobile and server.
- Designed the payment system for both Android and iOS apps.
- Supervised junior team members.
- Timely and quality delivery of Android application.
- · Managed Android team and drove efficient integration of development activities within the overall product delivery lifecycle.

2. Xingxing for Android

July 2014 - June 2015

Daily Active Users: 200 thousand (peak) Download Users: more than 5 million

It is an alarm clock app, by which users can wake people up through videos or voices.

I was responsible for

- Developed fundamental modules*(image/caching/networking), social modules(chat/ social update/fans/follows).
- · Released new versions.
- Monitored feedbacks and crash reports.
- Designed REST API for mobiles and servers.

*All of these modules were implemented by ourselves, of which the Open Source Code was released in my GitHub[1] [2] [3].

3. E-health for WinForm and Android

April 2013 - June 2014

This app is an outpatient infusion management system. It makes nurses easier to get the outpatients infusion information and increases their work efficiency.

I was responsible for the WinForm software on Windows, application on Windows Mobile and Android.

INTERESTS

In my spare time, I enjoy running marathon and have completed four times so far. I am also a fan of RC Helicopter and drones. I am open-minded and like to give anything a go.

^{*}Using Glide, RxJava, Retrofit, Otto etc to construct our app's fundamental modules.